Sheppard少校
Major Sheppard.
少校!
Major!
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第18集 天赋
Season 1 : Episode 18
The Gift
继续
Continue.
不把我放在心上, 啊?
Going easy on me, huh?
我向你保证, 少校, 不是的
I assure you, Major, I am not.
继续
Continue.
你没事吧?
You okay?
是的
Yes.
真的?
Are you sure?
以前可都是我被打倒在地上
Because it's usually me
picking my butt up off the mat.
说实话, 我没有睡好
Truthfully, I have not been sleeping much,
我总是在梦中看到幽灵
and when I do,
I've been having nightmares about the Wraith.
做这种恶梦的不仅仅是你一个人
Well, you're not the only one.
自从我父亲被掠走之后
还从来没有这么糟糕过
It has not been so bad since my father was taken.
根据Zelenka博士的计算
According to Dr. Zelenka's calculations,
据幽灵到达这里还剩不到一个星期了
we have less than one week before the Wraith arrive.
我需要一些方案
I want options.
你是说除了哭着进入梦乡之外?
You mean besides crying ourselves to sleep?
不是我
我已经有好些天没有睡觉了
Well, not me.
I haven't slept in days.
那么经过了这么多不眠之夜之后
你有什么可以展示给我们看的, Rodney?
And what do you have to show
for your sleepless nights, Rodney?
自从我们到这里以来, 除了防护罩
我们还找到了一些防御武器系统
Since we got here, we've uncovered a number
of defensive weapons systems beyond the shield...
- 我们认为我们最好的主意就是控制椅
- 这正是我想说的
- We think our best option is the control chair.
- I was going to say that.
- 是的, 不过你挨得太久了, 跟往常一样
- 不错, 不过我想说的是, 这可能不是我们最好的选择
- Yes, but you were taking too long, as usual.
- Yes, but the point is, this may not be our best chance.
- 那你再举一个更好的?
- 先生们
- Name a better one.
- Gentlemen.
当然, 跟防护罩一样
能量是我们最大的问题
Of course, like the shield,
power will be our biggest problem.
我们甚至不能让那座椅子完成初始化
We haven't even been able to initialize the chair yet,
更不用说找到足够的能量
让它运行起来
much less determine whether we can
meet the power requirements to run it.
好吧
有消息就通知我
Okay. Keep me posted.
Sergeant Bates, 阿尔法站点准备得怎么样了?
Sergeant Bates, where are we with our alpha site?
我们已经完成了地面和空中的防御
现在已经打扫干净, 可以建立大本营了
We've completed the ground and aerial security
sweep and are ready to begin establishing base camp.
我们现在在等Sheppard少校的最后验收
We're just awaiting final inspection by major Sheppard.
午饭后就去
Right after lunch.
很好
Good.
Teyla, Athosian准备好撤离了么?
Teyla, are the Athosians getting
prepared for an evacuation?
是的, 不过很多人认为
没有星球可以躲避幽灵的袭击
Yes, but many believe there is
no other world that is safe from the Wraith.
他们想留下?
They want to stay?
根据从盟友听到的消息以及我们的亲眼所见
幽灵正在这个星系的每个角落洗劫
As we have heard from our allies and seen for ourselves,
there are cullings happening all over the galaxy.
我们人民花费了他们的一生来躲避幽灵
My people have spent
their lives hiding from the Wraith.
是的, 现在不同的是
我们准备毁掉这座城市
Yes, well, the difference here
being we do intend to destroy the city
而不是让它落入幽灵之手
rather than let it fall into the hands of the Wraith,
如果是那样的话, 任何留在大陆的人
将会无法通过星际之门进行穿梭
and, if it comes to that, anyone left on the
mainland will be cut off from the Stargate for good.
还好, 感谢Rodney发现了星际之门的控制水晶
Now, thanks to Rodney's discovery
of the Gate's control crystal,
我们至少知道, 可以把它带上
希望它可以派上用场
we at least know we'll be able
to take that with us and hopefully use it
在未来某个时候可以再次访问地球
to access Earth again some time in the future.
我们知道了,  Weir博士
We understand that, Dr. Weir.
- 很抱歉, 我...
- I'm sorry, I...
我只是想说
Athos的人民想让你知道
I am merely saying that
the people of Athos wish you to know
如果我们想留下来战斗的话
他们也可以来帮忙保卫这座古人的城市
that if we are going to stay and fight,
they too will help defend the city of the ancestors.
- 这非常值得尊敬, 不过我...
- 噢, 行了!
- Well that is very honorable, but I...
- Oh please !
我们完全没有可能留下来战斗
We can't possibly consider staying and fighting.
我不同意
Well, I disagree.
我认为这完全在可能的范围之内
I think it's entirely within the realm of possibility.
成千上万凶神恶煞的敌人正坐着它们
高度先进的飞船在赶来干掉我们的途中
There are tens of thousands of life-sucking aliens in
highly advanced spaceships on their way here to destroy us.
而我们有什么, 200人,
而且大部分还是科学家
And we have what, 200 people,
most of whom are scientists
它们之前从来没有开过枪
who've never even fired a gun before?
虽然很不情愿, 而且这是第一次
我这次不得不同意Kavanagh
Shockingly, for the first time ever,
I find myself having to agree with Kavanagh.
我想说的是我们不要放弃... 现在还不能
All I'm saying is let's not give up... just yet.
那么我们大家都应该记住的东西是什么?
What was that we were supposed to all remember?
很重要的东西
Something important.
哦, 是的, 就是这个... Alamo
Oh, yes, that's right... the Alamo.
是的, 你们都是科学家
没人想把你们这些人送上前线
Granted, you guys are scientists. No one's
considering putting you guys on the front line,
不过科学家确实可以扭转战争
but science can turn the tide of war.
瞧瞧原子弹
Look at the a-bomb.
那并不是我们最自豪的时刻
Not exactly our proudest moment.
现在的事实是, 幽灵还没有到达这里
The fact is, the Wraith aren't here quite yet,
在那以前, 我希望每个人
都在做他们所能够做的最好的事情
and until that moment, I would like everyone
to remain focused on what it is they do best.
就像我最开始所说的
如果有任何可行的方案, 我需要它们
Like I said off the top,
if there are any options, I want them.
就这
That's all.
Teyla?
嗨
Hi.
Kate Heightmeyer
Kate Heightmeyer.
是的, 对
刚才想不起来了, 抱歉
Yes. Right.
I knew that. I'm sorry.
没关系
介意我坐在这里么?
No problem.
Mind if I join you?
不, 当然不会
No, of course not.
是不是觉得很奇怪, 在我们很累的时候
记忆就这样从脑海中溜走了
Strange how the memory
just goes away when we're tired.
- 你是一名医生, 对吧?
- 心理学家, 事实上
- You are a doctor, right?
- Psychologist, actually.
跟Beckett博士不同?
And that is different than Dr. Beckett?
是这样
Quite, yes.
我侧重于心理方面
I deal with the mind.
我帮助人们应对情绪上的问题
I try and help people deal with emotional problems,
就像焦虑, 沮丧, 外伤过后的精神抑制
like anxiety, depression, post-traumatic distress.
不必说, 自从我们到这以来
我一直都非常忙
Well, needless to say,
I've been pretty busy since we got here.
可以想象
I can imagine.
我知道你为你的人民做的事情
有很多跟我的工作类似
I'm sure that you do a lot of the
same things that I do for your people,
不过总是要保持一副勇敢的容貌
对你来说一定是非常困难
but it must be very hard on you,
always having to keep such a brave face.
力量来自于希望
From strength comes hope.
没有希望, 我的人民可能早就不复存在了
Without hope, my people would be lost.
你一定认为在我们面前
你也必须表现得非常坚强
You must feel you have to be
outwardly strong for us, as well.
Teyla, 我知道你的价值和你的忠诚
在过去曾经受到这里一小部分人的质疑
Teyla, I know that your value and your loyalty
have been questioned by a few here in the past.
不过我想告诉你的是
如果你需要与人谈谈的话, 我会乐意奉陪的
What I'm trying to say to you is,
if you ever need to talk, I'm here.
是Sheppard少校叫你来的吧?
Did major Sheppard ask you to speak with me?
是的, 他本可以...
Yes, he may have...
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我并不是有意冒犯, 不过我没事
I do not mean to be rude, but I'm fine.
真的
Really.
非常感谢你的关注
I appreciate your concern.
少校
Major.
Teyla
Teyla.
你告诉Heightmeyer什么了?
What did you tell Dr. Heightmeyer?
就是你所跟我说的那些
就是你无法入睡因为总是在做噩梦
Exactly what you told me. That you
couldn't sleep because you were having nightmares.
我是信赖你才跟你这样说的
I confided in you.
你是我的队伍中的一员
这让我有责任为你负责
You're a member of my team,
which makes you my responsibility,
而且我只告诉了一个人, 而她的工作
正是处理此类事情的
and I only told one person, whose job, by the way,
is to deal exactly with this sort of thing.
我的精神没有任何问题
There is nothing wrong with my mind.
没人说有问题
Nobody said there was.
为了让你的人尊敬我, 而不是认为我疯了
我一直都在努力
I have a hard enough time getting your people
to respect me without them thinking I'm crazy.
没人认为你疯了
而且每个人都很尊敬你
Nobody thinks you're crazy,
and everybody respects you.
不是这样的
That is not the point.
听我说, Teyla, 你可能需要休息一下
Look, Teyla, you may want to sit this one out.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
Rodney, Ford和我正准备去
Well, Rodney's staying back,
and Ford and I are just going to
最后检查一下阿尔法站点
在我们必须转移到那里之前
check out the alpha site
one last time before we have to move in.
如果我们必须撤离的话
我的人民也将被迫转移到哪个星球
Should we evacuate, my people
will be forced to that planet as well.
我保证对每个人来说
那里都会是安全的
And I'll make sure it's safe for everyone.
听着, Teyla, 我并不是说
你有什么地方不对劲
Look, Teyla, I'm not saying
there's anything wrong with you.
但愿不会这样, 不过你自己也承认
你的表现有些离谱
God forbid, but you yourself admitted
that you were a little off your game.
今天早上在报告厅
你无缘无故的呵斥Weir博士
You snapped at Dr. Weir this morning
in the briefing room for no good reason.
现在你又在朝我开火, 仅仅因为
我觉得你可能需要一些帮助
Now you're biting my head off
for caring that you might need help
因为已经三天了
你一直没法好好睡上一觉
dealing with the fact that it's been
three days since you've had any sleep.
我很抱歉, 不过我并不需要任何帮助
I'm sorry, but I do not need any help.
幽灵就要来了
我现在需要的就是做些什么
The Wraith are coming.
What I need is to do something.
是的, 很好
Okay. Good.
我建议你去打个盹
I suggest you take a nap.
- Teyla
- McKay博士
- Teyla.
- Dr. McKay.
我只是, 嗯...
I was just, um...
我们正彼此注视着对方
We're seeing each other.
你和Heightmeyer医生?
You and Dr. Heightmeyer?
你知道我是如何的喜欢
具有伟大... 思想的女人
Well, you know how much
I love women with great... minds.
请不要告诉... 任何人
Just don't say anything to... anyone.
我会替你保密的
Your secret is safe with me.
好的, 很好
Right. Very good. Excellent.
Heightmeyer医生?
Dr. Heightmeyer?
Teyla  请进
Teyla. Come in.
很抱歉打扰你了
I'm sorry to bother you.
- 我可不可以...
- 当然
- Is it all right if I...
- Of course.
请坐吧
Please, have a seat.
我并不是十分清楚这是如何工作的
I guess I'm not really sure
how this is supposed to work.
没事, 放松
Just relax.
告诉我你脑袋中所想的东西
Tell me whatever's on your mind.
我作过一些很恐怖的梦
I have been having bad dreams.
我感觉...
I feel...
在这个基地中的每个人可能都会觉得害怕
Everyone on this base is probably afraid.
- 我不知道我为什么到这里来打扰你...
- 你是不是总是感觉到幽灵?
- I do not know why I'm bothering you...
- Have you always been able to sense the Wraith?
是的, 自从我记事开始
Yes. Since I can remember.
这种感觉像是什么?
Well, what does it feel like?
感觉就像来自身体内部的一股很深的寒意
It feels like a deep cold that comes from within.
我第一次有这个感觉的时候
还是一个小女孩
I first felt it when I was a girl.
我无法呼吸, 然后不知道为什么
接着我就听到了幽灵的梭镖飞船
I could not breathe, and I did not know why,
and then we heard the darts.
你现在也是这样的感觉么?
Do you feel that way now?
我感觉我的心中有个结
将来某个时候就会发作
I have had a knot inside me for some time now.
据我所知, 它们的飞船
距离亚特兰蒂斯还有很长一段距离
As I understand, though,
their ships are still a great distance from Atlantis.
你真的能够从这么远的地方感觉到它们?
Can you really sense them from so far away?
这种感觉跟过去有一点不同
This feeling is a little different than in the past.
也许是因为它一直在那里
Perhaps it is because it is always there now.
我已经习惯了
I am getting used to it.
在我的一生中
还从来没有碰到这么多的幽灵醒来
Never before in my lifetime
have so many Wraith been awake.
你的人民当中, 很多人都有这个能力么?
Do many of your people have this ability?
有些人有
Some.
在这些人当中
一些人对幽灵的感觉更强一些
Among those few, some can
sense the Wraith stronger than others.
我总是第一个知道它们要来的人
I have always been among
the first to know they are coming.
这让你很特别
That makes you special.
这会让你有什么感觉?
How does that make you feel?
我不知道
我从来没有深入的思考这个问题
I do not know.
I suppose I have not given it much thought.
为什么不呢?
Why not?
为什么有些人的眼睛是蓝色
而其他人是褐色的?
Why do some people have blue eyes and others brown?
跟我讲讲你的噩梦
Tell me about your nightmares.
它就是我
It was me.
你站在你自己的身边?
You were standing over yourself?
它就是我... 不过它又不是我
It was me... but it was not me.
我是一个幽灵
I was a Wraith.
事实上, 人们浪费了大量的时间
试图解释它们的梦境
The truth is, people waste a lot of
time trying to interpret their dreams.
它们其实只是在我们睡觉时
我们大脑的另外一种思考方式
They're really just another way
our brain thinks when we're asleep.
并没有什么隐藏的含意
There are no hidden meanings.
实际上, 我们总是倾向于忘记
我们所梦到的几乎所有的东西
In fact, we tend to forget
most everything we dream about.
我们有意识的大脑能够判断
哪些东西对我们最为重要
Our conscious mind is capable
of deciding what's most important to us.
可是实际上, 在某种程度上,
我看到自己变成一个幽灵对我来说非常困惑
Well, the fact that, on some level,
I see myself as a Wraith is very disturbing to me.
我认为你所具有的这种特殊能力,
这种可以感觉幽灵的天性,
I think this special ability you have,
this talent for sensing the Wraith,
在你的意识中将你和它们联系起来,
而这也正是你试图抗拒的
connects you to them in your mind,
maybe in a way you would like to deny.
你说在过去从来没有真正的考虑这个问题
我认为这不是真的
You said you hadn't really given it much thought
in the past. I don't think that's true.
那我应该怎么做? 我又不能改变它
What am I supposed to do? I cannot change it.
也许是不行, 不过我们所害怕的
正是这些未知的东西
Probably not, but the unknown frightens us.
我们都愿意感觉一切都在控制之中
即便大部分时候我们的能力事实上还远远不够
We all like to feel in control, even though most of the
time our power over most things is just an illusion,
不过我发现我们对某样东西了解得越多
我们就越可以说服自己, 我们可以控制它
but I find the more we know about something, the more
we can convince ourselves we are in control of it.
我已经对你进行了我所能够采取的每项测试
I ran every test I could on all of you from the get-go.
从生理学上讲, 你和你的人民
跟我们是完全一样的
Physiologically, you and
your people are the same as we are.
我无法解释你所具有的那些超能力
I have no explanation for any
of your special super powers.
我只有一个
I only have one.
我看到过你战斗
I've seen you fight, my dear.
我过去曾经认为这种能力是
家族血统所遗传下来的
并以此作过一些追查
I have previously traced this ability as something
that is passed on through family lineage.
你说这不是生物学上的?
Does that not make it biological?
看起来应该是, 不过没有你的族谱中
每个人的基因样本
It would seem so, but without genetic samples
from everyone in your family tree,
我也无法标示出
引起这一生理学反映的基因片段
I would have little to no chance of identifying the specific
characteristic that causes the anatomical response.
这非常困难
It'd be difficult.
那如果你和我一同飞到大陆中去,
有没有这个可能呢?
Any chance you would have time
to fly me over to the mainland?
如果你想将你的生命掌握在你自己手中
If you're willing to take your life into your own hands.
我很乐意
I'd love a break.
你变了, Teyla
You've changed, Teyla.
我的头发变短了
My hair is shorter.
不止是你的头发, 亲爱的
It's more than your hair, dear.
我仍然还可以看到那个
常常为我画出美妙图画的小女孩
I can still see the little girl
who used to paint me beautiful pictures
那个唱着古人歌曲的小女孩
while she sang the songs of the Ancients.
我早就已经不是那个小女孩了, Charin
I have not been that girl in a long time, Charin.
不, 即便是Teyla, Athosian人的领袖,
也总是可以抽空来探访我, 老Charin, 这样卑微的人
No, but even Teyla, leader of the Athosians, always
found the time to come and visit with poor, old Charin.
我很想念你做的tuttleroot汤
I have missed your tuttleroot soup.
不过我想并不只是我的汤
让你来到这里
But I suspect it's more than my soup
that has brought you here.
你来这里是要把我拉出我的帐篷
并把我带到另外一个星球
You've come to pluck me from my tent
and take me to yet another world.
现在不是, 不过看起来我们可能不得不
再次撤离, 至少是暂时性的
Not yet, but it seems we may have
to evacuate again soon, at least temporarily.
假如实现不了, 你会答应么?
Did you allow yourself to expect differently?
我仍然相信终究有一天
我们可以从幽灵的阴影中解放出来
I still believe that we can
one day be free of the Wraith.
你可以为那些英勇献出自己生命的人
去讲这些故事
You can save such stories for those
whose bones aren't failing them.
Charin...
你知道为什么我会感觉到幽灵即将到来?
do you know why I can sense the Wraith coming?
你生来就是如此
You were born to it.
在每一代人中, 总有几个人具有这个能力
There have been a few in every generation.
我知道, 不过从来都没有人想过
为什么会这样么?
I know, but has no one ever
wondered how that is possible?
有些人认为这是祖先们所传下来的天赋
Some believe it was a gift from the ancestors.
你呢?
And you?
你父亲让我不要告诉你
Your father asked me not to tell you.
我父亲已经不在了
My father is not here anymore.
不能让其他活着的Athosian人知道
No other living Athosian
knows of this, for good reason.
求你了
Please.
无论如何告诉我吧
Tell me anyway.
我的祖父曾经告诉我一个故事...
My grandfather used to tell a story...
从来没有人听过的...
no one has ever heard the like, before or since...
关于少数被送回来的人
about the few who once returned.
被送回的?
Returned?
有一个星球...
There was a planet...
就跟我们所想到的一样
幽灵经常光顾那里
as was expected, every so often, the Wraith came,
村民被掠走, 不过那里
在这个特别的星球
villagers were taken, but there,
on this particular planet,
有几次, 被掠走的人又回来了
on several occasions, the taken came back.
有些人认为祖先们
将他们所珍爱的东西遗传了下来
Some believed that the ancestors
had returned their loved ones to them,
那种可以免受幽灵迫害的天赋
that they had been blessed with a gift
that made them unwanted by the Wraith.
还有人甚至还讲述了一些故事
那些被掠走的人如何征服了幽灵
Others even told tales of how the taken
had somehow vanquished the Wraith,
不过不久之后, 被掠走的人就开始感到害怕
but soon, the taken began to be feared.
为什么?
Why?
他们说听到了一些声音
They spoke of hearing voices.
很多人开始行为古怪
Many began to behave strangely.
有些人变得非常暴力, 甚至杀人
Some became violent, even murderous.
听起来好像
这并不是由古人所造成的
Well, it doesn't sound like
the Ancients were responsible for that.
不是
No.
村民们开始转向那些被掠走的人
这是一场大屠杀
The villagers turned on the taken. It was a massacre.
除了极少数, 大部分人都被杀死了
All but a few were killed.
剩下的人被放逐了
The rest were ostracized, sent away.
从那里后, 那个村子被掠走的人
就再也没有回来的了
After that, no others that were taken
from that village ever returned again,
不过那些活下来的, 他们就是那些
Charin所认为的传递天赋的人
but those few who survived, they are the ones
who Charin believes passed on the gift.
- 而有一个被掠走又活下来的人就是...
- 我的祖先
- And one of the taken that survived was...
-  My lineage.
我有发生这件事的星球的地址
I have the address to the planet where this happened.
Charin说那个村子早就不复存在了
Charin says the village is long gone.
剩下的只有废墟
不过我仍然很想去那里
All that is left are ruins,
but still, I wish to go there.
现在?
Now?
我认为发生这一切的原因
一定要大白于天下
I believe this must be coming to light now for a reason.
也许我们可以发现真正所发生事情的证据
Maybe we can find evidence of what really happened.
听着, Teyla, 我们还有很多事情要去做
Look, Teyla, there are a lot
of things that we need to get done.
也许这可以帮我们找到一个
抗击幽灵的方法
Maybe there is a way to fight
the Wraith that we have yet to discover.
或许我的祖先并没有达到足够的认知水平
以弄清楚这种天赋到底是什么
Perhaps my ancestors were simply not enlightened
enough to recognize their gift for what it was.
去看看没有什么大不了的
Doesn't hurt to take a look around.
- 长官, 这儿什么都没有
- 我知道
- Sir, there's nothing here.
- I know.
- 天黑了, 我们是不是该回去了?
- 再给她几分钟
- Well, it's dark. Shouldn't we be getting back?
- Give her a minute.
长官...
Sir...
Ford, 我需要她能够摆脱这一切
好好睡上一觉
Ford, I need her to put
this behind her, get some sleep.
我们大家这样做, 不管会发生什么
We all do so, whatever it takes.
Rodney?
我在这里收到一些信号
I've got something here.
真的么?
Really?
我不知道  我收到了一些...
I don't know. I've got a little...
你收到了一些什么?
You've got a little what?
嗨, McKay, 你收到了一些什么?
Hey, McKay, you've got a little what?
什么?
What?
哦, 你们这些家伙不要跟我开玩笑了
Oh, it's okay when you guys make fun of me.
Rodney?
收到一个微弱的能量信号
Picking up a faint energy signal.
变得越来越强了
It's getting stronger.
从这里发出的
Coming from here.
这里什么都没有
There's nothing here.
古人的设备到现在为止
还从来没有欺骗过我们
Well, the magic ancient device hasn't lied yet.
这是实心的
It's solid.
这里确实有些东西很奇怪
Well, there's definitely something weird here.
怎么奇怪?
Weird how?
- 那是怎么回事?
- Teyla!
- How about that?
Teyla!
如果你有一个良好的开端
也许, 你就可以冲进去
Maybe if you got a good running start.
You know, really slam into it.
你是怎么做到的?
How'd you do that?
我不知道
我只是在找出来的路
I do not know. I was just looking for a way out.
看起来像是在幽灵的飞船里面
Looks like the inside of a Wraith ship.
他们到底在这里做什么?
What the hell were they doing here?
Rodney.
Elizabeth.
Sheppard说你认为找到了一个幽灵的实验室?
Sheppard said you think you found a Wraith laboratory.
看起来像是
某种隐藏的秘密研究室
Certainly looks that way.
Some sort of hidden secret facility.
很明显被抛弃很长时间了
It's obviously been abandoned for a very long time.
我要把这个数据记录器
接入到某个计算机终端
I was able to pull this data recorder
from one of the computer consoles.
你认为幽灵是在
那个星球上的人身上做实验?
You think the Wraith were experimenting
on the people of that planet?
我也说不清楚
I have no idea.
- 希望这个东西能够告诉我们
- 它们为什么要保密呢?
- Hoping this thing will tell us.
- Why their need for secrecy?
幽灵可以随便掠走人们
用他们做任何想做的事情
The Wraith can take people at will
and do whatever they want with them.
搞定了
Here we go.
这里
There.
现在, 这个, 嗯...
Now, that, uh...
我对这个一窍不通
that means absolutely nothing to me.
上一次我见到类似的内容
展示的是一个飞船的星系定位系统
Last time I saw the contents of one of these,
it showed a galactic positioning system for ships.
它有更多的... 图像而不是符号
It was more... pictures than symbols.
我想...
I wonder...
你就知道这些
你实际上并没有读完那个句子
Just so you know, you didn't
actually finish that sentence out loud.
这很显然是一种语言
Well, this is obviously a language.
幽灵的语言?
Wraith language?
有理由相信是
That would make sense.
我想好好看看这个
I'd love to have a good look through this.
随便
Knock yourself out.
我要回去看看那个控制椅了
I have to get back to the control chair anyway.
你认为为什么你可以通过那道门
而其他人却不行呢?
Why do you think you could access
the doorway when no one else could?
我不知道
I don't know.
是不是因为只有幽灵
才可以进入那个秘密的研究室?
Is it because only a Wraith
can enter a secret Wraith facility?
我不是幽灵
I'm not a Wraith.
告诉我... 当幽灵的感觉如何?
Tell me... what does it feel like to be a Wraith?
我觉得很饿
I feel hunger.
你还记不记得最后一次
我坐在其中一个当中时发生了什么?
Don't you remember what happened
last time I sat in one of those?
现在的能量远远不够
这玩意儿什么也做不了
There's nowhere near enough power
in the thing to do anything.
那为什么还要搞得这么麻烦呢?
先生们, 已经很晚了
Then why bother? Gentlemen, it's quite late.
我们只是想判断一下到底需要多少能量
We are trying to determine exactly how much power
才能操纵由这个椅子所控制的系统
is required to operate the systems
that are controlled by the chair.
为了做到这一点, 它必须就必须启动
And in order to do that, it needs to be on.
你现在有这个基因了
You have the gene now.
是的, 不过我在集中精力想着
如何激活这个东西的时候
我就没有办法分析返回的数据了
Yeah, but I can't be trying to analyze
the feedback data while I'm concentrating
on keeping the damn thing activated.
你为什么不去分析一下它?
Why don't you analyze it?
是的, 我可以分析它
不过Rodney并不认为...
Well, I could analyze it,
but Rodney doesn't think that...
先生们, 怎么样了?
Gentlemen, how's it coming?
不好
Well, not good.
我很抱歉, 这帮不上忙
Carson, 我需要你
Well, I'm sorry.
This won't help. Carson, I need you.
噢, 感谢上帝
Oh, thank god.
不过我们正在用他
But we're using him.
- 怎么了? 有人受伤了?
- 你的理论是对的
- What is it? Is someone hurt?
- You were right.
真令人高兴  是关于什么的理论?
Lovely. About what?
那个幽灵是在古人到达飞马星系之后
开始进化的理论
Your theory of the Wraith evolving after
the Ancients arrived in the Pegasus galaxy.
简直是开玩笑
You've got to be kidding me.
(我赢了), 付钱吧
Pay up.
你怎么知道?
How do you know?
幽灵的语言是从古人的语言派生出来的
The Wraith language is a derivative of ancient.
那并不绝对就说...
Well, that doesn't categorically mean...
Rodney, 请听我说
Rodney, please.
那并不是我想见你的原因
That's not why I need to see you.
我已经能够翻译幽灵的数据设备中
记录的日志的第一部分了
I've been able to translate the first part
of the log from the Wraith data device.
真的么?
Really?
- 好了, 我们再试试Kusanagi博士
- 再试试Kusanagi
- All right, we'll try Dr. Kusanagi again.
- Kusanagi again.
- 马上
- 好的
- 谢谢
- Now.
- Okay.
- Thank you.
早上好
Good morning.
你看起来就像我担心的那样
You look like I fear.
我们整晚都没睡
Well, we've been up all night.
你想找我?
You wished to see me?
你最好坐下来
You'd better sit down.
怎么了?
What is it?
我翻译了你带回的日志的第一部分, 然后...
Well, I translated the first part
of the log you brought back, and...
你真的认为你不想坐下来?
are you sure you don't want to have a seat?
幽灵在你的祖先身上做了一些实验
The Wraith were conducting
experiments on your ancestors.
实际上, 只是一个幽灵
而且它这样做是违背了其它幽灵的意愿
It was just one Wraith, actually, and he was
doing it against the wishes of the other Wraith,
这就是为什么它要秘密进行
which is why he was doing it in secret.
他做了什么?
What was he doing?
我想他正试图让他们的食物来源
与他们这个物种更加协调
I think he was trying to make their
food source more compatible with their species.
我不明白
I do not understand.
这很难成功
It was very easy to miss.
事实上, 我甚至无法进行必需的比较
来分离特定的片断
In fact, I couldn't even make the kind of comparison
necessary to isolate the specific strand.
我们需要幽灵的细胞
这个我们终于得到了
We needed Wraith cells,
which we eventually got,
不过我们还需要包含在这些细胞中的
完整的基因图谱
but then we needed a full mapping of
the genetic code contained within those cells,
而这个还没有完成50%...
which wasn't even 50% complete...
求你了
Please.
告诉我
Tell me.
在你的遗传信息中, 含有一些幽灵的DNA
You have some Wraith DNA in your genetic makeup.
你在说Teyla有一部分是幽灵?
You're saying Teyla is part Wraith?
一个很小的部分
A very small part.
这让她同你一样, 跟我们不同
由于你所带有的古人的基因
Which makes her about as different from us as
you, because of the ancient gene you possess.
还有一些其它的东西
Well, and some other things.
如果知道这个, Bates就会发狂的
Still, Bates is going to go nuts over this.
我们先不要把这个公布出去
Let's just keep this one under our hat.
是的, 很显然Teyla将会非常在意每个人的反应
Well, obviously Teyla is very concerned
about how everyone will react.
怎么, 这么说你认为这个幽灵科学家
正试图让人类, 怎么说呢, 更可口?
What, so you think this Wraith scientist was
trying to make humans what, more tasty?
日志看起来是在说明他正在试图寻找一种方法
以让取食的过程更加有效
The log seems to indicate that he was looking for a
way to make the feeding process more efficient.
我想你说过它们具有一些
类似于人类的基因特征
I thought you already said they had a number
of genetic characteristics similar to humans.
确实是这样, 不过相比我们而言, 它们还是
更接近于攻击Sheppard 少校的麻烦制造者
They do, but they're still much closer to the bug
creature that attacked major Sheppard than to us.
嗨, 不要再提那个了好么
Hey, I thought we weren't
going to mention that anymore.
抱歉
Sorry.
同时令我们感兴趣的还有幽灵的语言
看起来是从古人的语言派生出来的
Also interesting is the fact that the Wraith
language appears to be a derivative of ancient,
这就意味着幽灵是在
古人到达飞马星系之后发展起来的
which seems to suggest that the Wraith
evolved after the Ancients arrived in Pegasus.
我的理论就是古人无意中
允许人类在一个星球上进化
My theory is that the Ancients unwittingly
allowed humans to evolve on a planet
同时还有... 昆虫物种在上面
with the... insect species on it.
在某种情况下, 这些昆虫以人类为食
并且不知为何将我们的DNA结合进了它们的DNA
At some point, the insects fed on humans and
somehow incorporated our DNA into theirs.
幽灵就是这种组合所进化出来的结果
The Wraith are an evolution of that combination.
照你这么说, 实际上是古人创造了幽灵?
So, what you're saying is the
Ancients actually created the Wraith?
不经意间
By accident.
或者是疏忽
Or negligence.
不管是哪种方式, 这都无所谓了
Well, either way, it doesn't matter.
从根本上说, 在生理学上我们对幽灵了解得越多,
我们就越有可能制造出一种生物武器
Ultimately, the more we know about Wraith physiology,
the closer we get to a biological weapon
用它来袭击幽灵, 保护人类免受伤害
that can attack the Wraith and leave humans unharmed.
是的, 不过此时, 我们所知道的就是
古人可能偶然间制造了幽灵
Yes, but for the moment, all we know is that the
Ancients might have accidentally created the Wraith,
以及为什么Teyla可以感觉到它们的到来
and why Teyla can sense them coming.
具有讽刺意味的是, 秘密揭开了,
不过不管是哪个都无法帮助我们阻止它们的到来
I mean, fabulous, mystery solved, but neither of
which that help, in any way, stop them from coming.
Rodney是对的
Rodney's right.
让我们回去干活吧
Let's get back to work.
谢谢
Thank you.
我知道这不是我的错
I know that it is not my fault.
我什么也做不了
There's nothing I can do about it.
事实上, 我现在跟昨天
以及上星期没有什么不同
The fact is, I'm really no different now
than I was yesterday or last week.
不过你感觉到不同了
But you feel different.
是的
Yes.
我想我最担心的就是人们会如何看待我
I think the thing that I am most
worried about is how people will perceive me.
我的父亲告诉人们, 我与众不同
这是天赋
My father told people that it was a gift,
that I was special, but in a good way.
我可以帮助我的人民
通知他们幽灵即将到来
I could help my people by warning
them of the Wraith's approach.
他这样做是为了保护我, 不过在多数情况下, 我想
这也是为什么他们首先把我当作首领的原因
He did it to protect me, but in many ways, I think
that it is why they first turned to me as a leader.
正如你刚才所说的,
你跟昨天没有什么不同
As you just said, you're no
different than you were yesterday.
是的, 不过现在他们有理由害怕我了
Yes, but now they have reason to fear me.
好了, 即便是Sheppard坐在那个椅子中
我们仍然不能...
All right, even with major Sheppard in
the chair, we weren't able to...
怎么了?
What is that?
你所说的让我想起...
Something you said made me wonder...
我想我们所决定的
应该是更重要的事情...
I thought we decided there
were more important things...
为什么幽灵科学家停止了实验?
why did the Wraith scientist stop the experiments?
我说过的什么让你想起了这个?
What would I have said that
would make you think that?
我记不起来了
I don't remember.
这真是... 真是一个好问题
我只是想知道我说过的什么...
Well, it's just... it's a good point.
I'm just wondering what I said that...
抱歉, 你想到了什么?
Sorry. What have you got?
首先, 我认为是其它幽灵抓住了他
Well, at first I thought it was
because the other Wraith caught him.
他们没有?
They didn't?
没有, 根据这个, 他是自己停止的
No, according to this, he stopped on his own.
现在你的话让我想搞清楚为什么
其它幽灵不想这些实验在第一个地方进行
See, now you've got me wondering why the rest
of the Wraith didn't want these experiments
taking place in the first place.
很对
Exactly.
特别是当它们每个人都可以从中获益的时候
Especially since they were supposed to
be intended to improve things for everyone.
是的, 我也是这样想的
Yeah. That's what I'm saying.
我刚说的
I just said it.
你可以停一下么?
Will you stop?
OK, 现在是最重要的部分...
Okay, here's the most interesting part...
幽灵使用某种心灵感应网络来相互交流
The Wraith communicate with each
other using some sort of telepathic network.
我注意到了
I noticed that.
幸运的是
Thankfully,
它们还不能读取人类的心灵
they can't seem to read the
minds of humans, though.
这很好, 不过这跟幽灵停止试验
有什么关系呢?
That's good, but what does this have
to do with the Wraith stopping the experiments?
因为, 通过将哪怕是很小一部分的
幽灵DNA组合到人类的DNA当中
Because, by combining even small
amounts of Wraith DNA with humans,
那个科学家赋予了人类幽灵的精神能力
the scientist was giving the
humans Wraith mental abilities.
他那些试验的受实验者
能够听到幽灵的通信
The subjects of his experiments were
able to hear the Wraith communications.
Teyla所讲述的故事中,
那些人们所听到的声音就是...
In the stories that Teyla told,
the voices that the people heard were...
是幽灵, 其实
were Wraith. Exactly.
这很可能让他们发疯
It must have driven them mad.
那个幽灵科学家找不到解决办法
所以最终他放弃了
The Wraith scientist couldn't find a
way around it, so eventually he gave up.
我不理解
I don't understand.
我是说, 他为什么又让他们回到人群当中呢?
I mean, why let them back in
the general population, then?
看起来他认为这样与普通人类
杂种繁殖之后应该会削弱这种反应
Well, it seems he thought that interbreeding
with normal humans might dilute the effect.
当他认为这种想法错了的时候
已经太迟了
Before he realized he was wrong, it was too late.
当其它幽灵发现了他所做的一切之后
它们那个星球上的所有人一扫而光
When the other Wraith did find out what he had
done, they wiped out all the people on the planet...
不过这是在一些受实验者被放逐以及
被迫离开之后
but not before several of the test subjects had
already been ostracized and forced to leave.
好吧, 这对我们有什么帮助?
Okay, so how does this help us?
Teyla可能不仅仅只有可以感觉到
幽灵即将到来的能力
Teyla may have more than just
the ability to sense the Wraith coming.
你是说你认为Teyla可能可以...
You're saying you think Teyla might be able to...
接入到幽灵的精神网络?
tap into this Wraith psychic network?
如果她可以的话, 我们就能够收集到
所有我们需要的关于它们的内部信息
If she can, we'll be able to gather
all the intel we ever needed about them.
我以前从来没有听到过幽灵的思考
I have never been able to hear
the thoughts of the Wraith before.
根据笔记的记载, 所有的被赋予幽灵DNA的
受测试者, 都有这个能力
According to the notes, all the test subjects
who were given the Wraith DNA, they had the ability.
可能是因为你以前从来没有尝试过
It's possible it's because
you've never actually tried before.
你不知道你可以读取幽灵的心灵,
而且很坦白的说, 谁曾想过?
You didn't know you could read Wraith
minds, and quite frankly, who would want to?
听着, Teyla, 如果我认为这不会给我们
带来一些潜在的重要的信息的话
Look, Teyla, I would not even
consider asking you to do this
我不会要求你这样做的
if I didn't think it could potentially
provide us with some vital information.
我只是不知道我该怎么去做
I just do not know what to do.
好吧, Heightmeyer医生有办法
Well, Dr. Heightmeyer has a theory.
我认为有可能, 经过漫长的时间,
经过很多代人之后
I think it's possible that, over time,
through several generations,
具有你这种能力的人
已经建立起了一道心理上的防线
people with your ability have developed a mental
barrier to the thought projections of the Wraith.
某种自我保护机制
Sort of a self-defense mechanism.
如果我们可以穿过那道...
If we can get past that...
怎样穿过?
How?
我们有一种被称作催眠的治疗方法
We have a treatment process called hypnosis.
Heightmeyer可以引导你穿过它
Dr. Heightmeyer can lead you through it,
而且Beckett博士将会一直守在旁边
监视你的身体状况
and Dr. Beckett will remain on hand
at all times to monitor your physiology.
幽灵仍然还在非常远的地方, 是不是?
The Wraith are still very far away, are they not?
是的, 而且McKay, 他确实也对心灵感应的范围
有一些疑虑
Yes, they are, and McKay, he does have
some doubts about the range of this telepathy.
不过如你所说的
你现在已经可以感觉到幽灵了
But as you've said, you can sense the Wraith now.
如果这可以激发你意识中
一个更大的潜能的话
If that's merely a bleed-through effect
into your consciousness of a greater latent ability,
那么就值得去打破这道心理防线
then it may be worth trying to break the barrier.
非常诚实的讲, 如果是在其它情况下
我是不会推荐这样做的
To be perfectly honest, it's not something I would
ever recommend doing under any other circumstances.
不过现在已经远不是平常的情况了, Teyla
But these are far from normal
circumstances that we're in, Teyla.
如果我确实可以为我们提供一些东西...
If I can somehow provide us with something...
它们的战略, 某个弱点...
their strategy, a weakness...
我看我别无选择
I see no other choice.
好了, 我认为已经准备好了
Okay, I think we're ready.
好了么?
Are you?
OK, 我现在要你呼吸...
Okay, I want you to breathe...
完全的, 深深的呼吸, 并且尽量的放松
nice and deeply, and try to relax.
Beckett博士准备注射一计轻度的镇静剂
Dr. Beckett's going to administer a mild sedative.
如果这奏效的话
我们应该还可以彼此间对话
Now, if this works, we should still be able
to communicate with each other.
记住, 我们任何时候都可以
使用一个非常低等级的电流来唤醒你
Remember, we can wake you at any time,
using a very low-grade electrical current.
这不会造成任何伤害的
It won't hurt at all.
如果想停止, 就说"out", 我们马上就会停下来
Just say, "out", and we'll end it.
现在, 在我说话的时候注视这个灯光
Now, focus on this light as I speak.
你跟我说过, 你从幽灵那里得到的就是
来自于身体内部的寒冷, 黑暗的感觉
You told me that the feeling that you get
from the Wraith is a cold, dark feeling deep inside you.
我要你想着这个感觉
I want you to think about that.
在你的头脑中寻找这个感觉
Look for it in your mind.
现在,  闭上眼睛, 仔细聆听
Now, close your eyes and listen to it.
不要抵抗
Don't resist.
顺其自然
Go to that place where it lives.
你听到了什么?
What do you hear?
什么也没有
Nothing.
你跟我说过你的父亲被幽灵掠走
You told me that your father was taken by the Wraith.
你还记不记得自那以后的感觉?
Do you remember sensing it that day?
是的
Yes.
后头想想那种感觉
Think back to that feeling.
现在仔细听
Now listen.
你听到了什么?
What do you hear?
噪声
Noise.
说话声, 很多说话声, 窃窃私语
Voices, so many voices, whispering.
靠近些去听
Listen closely.
听一个声音
Listen for one.
我可以看到了
I can see.
告诉我们你看到了什么, Teyla
Tell us what you see, Teyla.
我在一艘飞船上
I am on a ship.
我在走路
I am walking.
她真的看到了正在发生的事情?
She can actually see what's happening?
如果幽灵可以发射出他们的思维,
那么那就可以包括它们所看到的东西
If the Wraith can project their thoughts,
then that may include what they're seeing.
有其它幽灵
There are other Wraith.
它们没有注意到我
They do not notice me.
我在一个房间中, 四周贮藏满了人
以便它们取食
I am in a room full of people being preserved
so that they can be fed upon.
我正在取食
I am feeding.
我正在杀死他
I am killing him.
停止. Beckett, 停止
Stop. Beckett, stop.
没事了
It's okay.
没事了, 你在这里, 在亚特兰蒂斯
It's okay. You're here, in Atlantis.
Teyla, 我...
Teyla, I...
我没有权利要求你这样做
I had no right to ask you to do this.
把这些东西从我身上拿开
Get these things off of me.
好的, 平静下来, Teyla.
All right, settle down, Teyla.
我会把这个拿掉
I have to take this off.
我不能让她做这些, John.
I can't put her through this, John.
我知道这是我的主意, 不过它的代价太大
I know it was my idea, but it's too much to ask.
当幽灵的母船出现的时候
你可能就会是另外一种想法
You might feel differently once the hive ships show up.
Weir博士
Dr. Weir.
你为什么让他们停下来?
Why did you make them stop?
对不起?
Excuse me?
我正在前往这里的一艘母船上
I was on one of the hive ships that is headed here.
我可以听到他们
I could hear them.
我可以看到
I could see.
这是有效的
It was working.
你看到它们正在取食
You were watching them feed.
是的
Yes.
我确实感觉到它们当中有一个正在取食
I actually felt one of them feed,
不过我可以承受
but I can handle it.
你可以帮助我们, 我知道
I can help us, I know it.
Teyla, 我不会再...
Teyla, I never should've...
我要再试一次
I am going to try again.
我正走过飞船
I am walking through the ship.
我在某个控制室中
I am in some sort of control room.
你们都是如此的可怜
You are all so pathetic.
我觉得这不是Teyla在说话
Something tells me that's not Teyla talking.
没有什么可以阻止我们
Nothing can stop us.
唤醒她
Wake her up.
你们都将去死
You are all going to die.
马上!
Now!
发生什么了?
What happened?
Beckett已经给她服用了镇静剂
她现在正在休息
Dr. Beckett has her sedated,
and she's resting comfortably.
她看起来没事, 不过我需要一些时间
来了解她看到了什么
She seems fine, but I would like some time
to let what she's been through sink in.
她可能是受到了惊吓
She may still be in shock.
我不知道会不会有长期的心理影响
I have no idea what
the long-term psychological effect will be.
她说她可以看到某种控制室...
也许一张地图, 一份攻击计划
She said she could see some type
of control room... maybe a map, an attack plan.
她需要更仔细的看一下
She just needs to get a better look.
John, 你当时在那里
John, you were there.
一个幽灵控制了她
A Wraith had control of her.
有虫洞连接进来
Incoming wormhole.
我们收到了Bates上士的身份识别码
We're getting sergeant Bates' I.D.C.
是阿尔法站点
It's the alpha site.
我是Bates上士
This is sergeant Bates.
红色代码 我们正受到攻击, 正急速赶来!
Code red. We're under attack and coming in hot!
放下防护盾
Lower the shield.
快, 快!
Move it, move it!
好了, 我们都到了
That's it, we're clear.
升起防护盾!
Raise the shield!
所有人都还好吧?
Is everybody okay?
所有回来人员报道
All off-world personnel accounted for.
我想那个星球已经不再安全了
I guess that planet isn't safe anymore.
它们坐飞船出现在那里
They showed up by ship,
在我们准备离开的时候
在星际之门的旁边丢下某种设备
and dropped some sort of device
by the Gate as we were leaving.
我以前见过
I've seen it before.
它们在标记那个星球
They're tagging the planet.
如我我们要从亚特兰蒂斯撤退
我们需要另外选一个地方
If we're going to evacuate Atlantis,
we're going to need a new place to go.
那个星球应该无人居住
That planet was supposed to be uninhabited.
幽灵过去想要什么?
What did the Wraith want with it?
我不知道
I don't know.
看起来它们好像知道我们在那里
It's almost like they knew we were there.
我已经接近了, 我已经很近了
I was close. I was so close.
我认为如果我还有一次机会...
I really think if I had another chance...
嗨, 你没有必要向这里的每个人
证明所有事情
hey, you don't have to prove
anything to anyone around here.
我认为这可以带来一些改变
I think this could make a difference.
我看到一个全息图
I saw a hologram.
我想那是一幅地图
I think it was a map,
甚至可能是一个作战计划
maybe even a battle plan.
我们知道它们的作战计划
We know their battle plan.
它们要来把我们清除掉
They're coming to wipe us out.
我不是十分肯定这是真的
I'm not so sure that is true.
它们需要从我们这里得到一些东西
They want something from us.
是的, 是的, 他们想吃掉我们
Yeah. Yeah, they want to eat us.
不, 不仅仅是这些
No, something more.
它们在孤注一掷
They are desperate.
真的么?
Really?
是的, 很令人惊奇
Yes, it is surprising.
它们对征服我们非常有信心,
不过这主要是因为它们的数量非常之多...
They are confident in their dominance over us,
but mainly because there are so many of them...
太多了以至于无法维持很长的时间
too many to sustain for long.
它们都过早的醒来,
而四周没有足够的食物
They have all awakened early,
and there is not enough food to go around.
这只是一种感觉
It was just a feeling.
那种声音很难分离出来
The voices were so hard to separate.
你记不起来其中一个通过你所说的话?
You don't remember one of them speaking through you?
不, 不过我记得在这以前的感受
No, but I remember the feeling just before it happened.
下一次...
Next time...
我想 Weir 博士不会允许再进行一次了
I don't think Dr. Weir will let there be a next time.
如果你说的是真的, 那么就有可能是
Teyla将我们的阿尔法站点的位置告诉给了幽灵
if what you're saying is true, then chances are
it was Teyla who gave away the location
of our alpha site to the Wraith.
我认为没有足够的时间
I don't think there was time.
你不知道它们在那个区域没有飞船
You don't know that they didn't
have a ship in the general area.
我同意, 现在回想起来, 要求Teyla
连接到幽灵, 这可能是一个错误
Look, I admit, in retrospect, asking Teyla
to connect with the Wraith, it may have been a mistake.
很客气地说, 我认为这是毋庸置疑的
With all due respect,
I don't think there's much doubt about that.
放松一下, 上士
Take it easy, sergeant.
她并不是有意想透漏我们的位置
It's not like she willfully gave away our position.
她想再试一次
She wants to try again.
她说她已经接近某个非常重要的东西
某件她可以说服我们去了解的东西
Look, she says she was getting close to something big,
something she's convinced we need to know.
不行, 我很抱歉
No. I'm sorry.
问题是, 我不敢保证Teyla所想的
是对她最有利的
The problem is, I'm not sure Teyla's thinking
about what's best for herself.
同时她可能更加威胁我们的安全
Or that she could compromise us further.
从这一点来说, 相比它们了解我们的
我们需要从幽灵那里了解更多
At this point, we have more to gain
from the Wraith than they do from us.
她想要去做
She wants to do it.
事实是, 我们没有什么可以阻止她去尝试
所以如果我们都在那里是不是更好?
Fact is, there may not be anything we can do to stop her
from trying, so isn't it better if we're all there?
好吧
Okay.
闭上你的眼睛, 放松, 聆听那些声音
Close your eyes and relax, and listen for the voices.
Teyla?
终端连接
Break the connection.
没有作用
It's not working.
不要!
No!
Teyla!
我只能希望, 我们没有给她造成心理损害
I can only hope we haven't
caused her psychological damage.
Teyla是我所认识的最强健的人之一
Teyla's one of the strongest people I know.
事实上她可以在以前走过的日子中
很好的处理这些...
The fact that she's been able to hold it together
until now after what she's been through in her life...
你们在这里
now, there you are.
少校, Weir博士
Major, Dr. Weir.
Carson, 你感觉怎么样?
Carson, how are you feeling?
有些头疼, 不过我没事
Doozy of a headache, but I'll be fine.
Teyla醒了
Teyla's awake.
她想见你们两个
She wants to see both of you.
Teyla, 你口渴么? 我可以给你倒些水么?
Teyla, are you thirsty? Can I get you some water?
不用
No.
我很抱歉
I am so sorry.
我本以为我可以阻止...
I really thought I could prevent...
没事, 所有人都还好
it's all right. Everyone's fine.
我们所关注的是幽灵可以任意连接你
We are concerned that the Wraith
can connect to you at will, though.
这以前从来没有发生过?
It has never happened before?
不, 我肯定我必须首先连接到他们
No, I am sure I have to connect with them first.
我看到了它们的计划,
I saw their plans,
它们的飞船来到这里的路线
the route their ships are taking to get here.
很好
That's good.
还有
There's more.
它们想要的不仅仅是亚特兰蒂斯
They do not just want Atlantis.
它们了解你们
They know about you.
什么意思?
What do you mean?
Sumner
Sumner.
那个母幽灵并不仅仅是取食他
The female Wraith wasn't just feeding on him.
她在审问他
She was interrogating him.
这就是为什么它们全部都醒来
That is why they're all waking up.
这就是为什么它们要来这里
That is why they are coming here.
它们知道亚特兰蒂斯是唯一通往
一个全新的, 富饶的取食场的通道
They know that Atlantis is the only way to get
to a new, rich feeding ground.
地球
Earth.